Mohit Jindal

Sahibzada Ajit Singh Nagar, Punjab, India



mohitjindal1212@gmail.com



9041700225



linkedin.com/in/mohit-jindal-97180282

Summary

Actively looking for job opportunities in Dubai, Singapore, Malaysia. Sales & Marketing Manager with 11+ years of experience Proven ability to deliver quality results across operational, planning, marketing, public relations, client services, sales and brand management. Work alongside company owners analyzing monthly sales reports to determine factory production and inventory control Support relationships with major accounts Help facilitate the entire process of private-label productions from order entry to final delivery. Skills

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Order Processing, Customer Service, Marketing, Sales, Account Management, Office Administration, Office Management, Retail Management, Accounts Receivable, Clerical, Client Relationship Management

Experience



Marketing Manager

Vapco Industries

Jul 2020 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

Vapco Industries, certified from ISO 9001:2005, food contract packaging material company the foremost manufacturer and supplier of superior quality range of (Curd, Yogurt Cups, Ice Cream Cups, Kheer Cups, Rasgulla Cups, and Disposable Lassi Cup.) the products in India for pioneer brands (Amul, Mother Dairy, Cream bell, Namaste India, Verka, Vadilal, Vita, etc. Follows the Food Safety Policy and Quality Management System.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1. Responsible for Managing Customer Business Communication by taking approvals on samples, providing quotations, Performa invoices, sharing dispatch details, getting pending payments and providing confirmation to all cooperate customers.
- 2. Direct responsibility for maintaining and improving the customer satisfaction on supplied range of products by determining, evaluating in house production practices.
- 3. Resolve issues and solve problems that may occur throughout the lifecycle of the project.
- 4. Involved in the filling of online tenders.
- 5. Creating an effective marketing plan
- 6. Developing a pricing strategy that maximizes profits and market share but considers customer satisfaction.
- 7. Offering solutions & CAPA reports to complaints generated by clients
- 8. Preparing sales report by various parameters wise.
- 9. Handle the processing of all orders with accuracy and timeliness.

Area Sales Manager

Corn Troopers

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 months)

A startup company setup in May 2019 by a retired school principal that manufactures various types of ready to eat popcorns (100% Vegan). Started its first unit in Derra Bassi. Follows food safety policies and uses eco friendly packing.

Role and Responsibility:

- 1. Appoint new distributors in the North region by checking the feasibility of the distributors.
- 2. Manage primary, secondary and tertiary sales.
- 3. Handle General Trade & Modern Trade, Adept at identifying and developing key clients for business excellence and accomplishment of targets.
- 4. Develops Sales plans and budgets to achieve or exceed the annual sales objectives for the company.
- 5. Monitor and control the sales budget to ensure optimum utilization of resources in the region.
- 6. Conduct regular market visits to check route coverage, competitor activity and continuously search for new opportunities in order to increase sales in the region.
- 7. Develop and maintain an efficient distribution network to ensure the comprehensive availability of company's products and services across the region to achieve or exceed the sales targets.



North head marketing

Edutalent Sgi private limited

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019 (2 years)

Lifestraw is a brand of water filtration and purification devices, the water filters are designed by the swiss-based vestergaard frandsen, lifestraw® purifiers, which are gravity-fed, high-volume, point-of-use microbiological water purifiers and a reliable investment in the health and wellbeing of the vulnerable rural population. It removes almost all waterborne bacteria, microplastics and parasites. A bottle was later developed which incorporated a lifestraw cartridge into a 650-millilitre (22 us fl oz) bpa-free plastic sports water bottle. Built-in safe storage container with tap. Doesn't require electrical power, batteries or replacement parts.

Role and Responsibilities:

- 1. Set the budget every quarter for marketing spend with VP of Finance and Admin
- 2. Build KPI for weekly reporting to show impacts from the marketing department
- 3. Work closely with sales, product, and account management teams to generate leads for the business
- 4. Entrepreneurial skills and instinct in undertaking high-level strategic analysis and planning, together with the development of innovative value propositions for customers
- 5. To manage the work programs of relevant staff to ensure optimum productivity, personal development and impact on EMDP KPIs
- 6. Build marketing plans and budgets for the smooth operation of marketing campaigns.
- 7. Lead the development of marketing plans working closely with clients, management, creative and content teams, and distribution partners, to create an effective and efficient marketing strategy focused on growing audiences for our products and services
- 8. Spearhead the strategic and tactical execution of marketing campaigns, including design of test/control segmentation, implementation of tests, tracking, results reporting, analysis, and recommendations
- 9. Attend and participate at conventions, conferences, and tradeshows, preparing engaging displays and collateral as needed, and providing post-event reports and analysis



Area Sales Manager

Kemp Product

Jan 2011 - Dec 2017 (7 years)

Kemp Products is one of the leading manufacturers of trophies, mementoes, plaques, corporate gifts, awards, model making, acrylic ramp, laser engraving, souvenirs, name plates, drop boxes, display boards, scientific fabrication, transparent furniture, transparent covers podiums, they work with nonmetals that includes acrylic, wood, crystal, row mark sheets the raw material used by us does not require maintenance. Company has the latest American laser engraving plant and the production base in Dehradun. They custom design products and execute job orders to clients satisfaction in the given time frame.

Role and Responsibilities:

- 1. Take orders from government sector (Schools, tax department, irrigation department, transport department, railways and banks).
- 2. Maintaining and increasing sales of company's products in assigned areas included Himachal, Haryana, Punjab, Jammu and Kashmir.
- 3. Servicing the needs of existing customers.
- 4. Recruiting and training sales staff and Allocating areas to sales representatives.
- 5. Monitoring the team's performance and motivating them to reach targets and help them to achieve their target by accompanying sales team.
- 6. Good planning and organisational skills and ability to work calmly under pressure.
- 7. Utilizing outbound telephone calls, email communications, and face-to-face meetings with customers to close sales.

Education



Panjab University, Chandigarh

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Mathematics Jan 2008 - May 2011

Skills

Leadership • Growth Marketing • Team Management • B2B Marketing • B2C Marketing • Teamwork · Customer Relationship Management (CRM) · Marketing · Sales · Strategy